ZHIHAO XIA

zxia@adobe.com \$ https://likesum.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests include computer vision, computational photography, and machine learning. I am particularly interested in building methods that can recover different aspects of visual appearance (geometry, light, colors, etc.) from images, by using both physics-based reasoning and machine learning.

EDUCATION

Washington University in St. Louis

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Ph.D. in Computer Science & Engineering Advisor: Ayan Chakrabarti

University of Science and Technology of China

Sep 2013 - Jun 2017

B.S. in Computer Science, School of the Gifted Young

Honor: National Scholarship (Top 2%)

EXPERIENCE

Adobe
Jun 2021 - Present
Research Scientist
CA. USA

· Using computational photography and machine learning to build next-gen camera for mobile devices.

Google Research

May 2020 - Dec 2020

Research Intern

WA, USA

· Worked with Supreeth Achar and Jason Lawrence on face relighting and normal estimation under challenging visible light environments by supplementing a near-infared image.

Adobe Research
Research Intern

May 2019 - Aug 2019 *CA*, *USA*

- · Worked with Federico Perazzi, Michaël Gharbi, Kalyan Sunkavalli on Basis Prediction Networks.
- · Research was transferred into products and published in CVPR 2020.

Washington University in St. Louis

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Research Assistant

MO. USA

- · Member of WashU vision and learning group directed by Prof. Ayan Chakrabarti.
- · Computer Vision, Computational Photography and Deep Learning.

King Abdullah University of Science and Technology

Jan 2017 - May 2017

Visiting Student Researcher

Jeddah, SAU

· Worked with Prof. Xin Gao on recognition of polyadenylation signal (PAS) in human and mouse genes with CNN.

National University of Singapore

July 2016 - Nov 2016

Visiting Student Researcher

Singapore

· Worked with Prof. Richard Ma on investigating Internet topology with Multiple Hidden Markov Chains.

University of Science and Technology of China

June 2015 - June 2016

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Hefei, China

· Topic diffusion analytics in social media based on machine learning.

PUBLICATION

- 1. Ilya Chugunov, Yuxuan Zhang, **Zhihao Xia**, Cecilia Zhang, Jiawen Chen, Felix Heide. "The Implicit Values of A Good Hand Shake: Handheld Multi-Frame Neural Depth Refinement", arXiv, 2021.
- 2. Zhihao Xia, Jason Lawrence, Supreeth Achar. "A Dark Flash Normal Camera", ICCV, 2021.
- 3. **Zhihao Xia**, Michaël Gharbi, Federico Perazzi, Kalyan Sunkavalli, Ayan Chakrabarti. "Deep Denoising of Flash and No-Flash Pairs for Photography in Low-Light Environments", *CVPR*, 2021.
- 4. **Zhihao Xia**, Federico Perazzi, Michaël Gharbi, Kalyan Sunkavalli, Ayan Chakrabarti. "Basis Prediction Networks for Effective Burst Denoising with Large Kernels", *CVPR*, 2020.
- 5. **Zhihao Xia**, Patrick Sullivan, Ayan Chakrabarti. "Generating and Exploiting Probabilistic Monocular Depth Estimates", *CVPR*, 2020 (Oral).
- 6. **Zhihao Xia** and Ayan Chakrabarti. "Identifying Recurring Patterns with Deep Neural Networks for Natural Image Denoising", WACV, 2020.
- 7. **Zhihao Xia** and Ayan Chakrabarti. "Training Image Estimators without Image Ground-Truth", NeurIPS, 2019 (Spotlight)
- 8. **Zhihao Xia**, Yu Li, Bin Zhang, Yuhui Hu, Wei Chen and Xin Gao. "DeeReCT-PolyA: a robust and generic deep learning method for PAS identification", *Bioinformatics*, 2018.
- 9. Yu Sun, **Zhihao Xia** and Ulugbek S. Kamilov. "Efficient and accurate inversion of multiple scattering with deep learning", *Optics express* 26(11): 14678-14688, 2018.

SKILLS

Python: Numpy, Tensorflow, PyTorch. C/C++. Matlab

SERVICE

- Reviewer for IJCV, TIP, CVPR (2021), ICCV (2021, 2019), IJCAI (2021, SPC), WACV (2020)
- Assistant to Instructor, WashU Fall 2018 CSE 559A: Computer Vision. Developed and held recitation lectures, assisted with grading, staffed office hours to assist students
- Co-organizor: WashU CS Graphics, Vision, and Imaging Seminar, Fall 2019 and Spring 2020